Ashish Kumar

Kanpur (UP)



agnihotri.ashishkumar25@gmail.com



A highly self-motivated and enthusiastic Web Application Developer offering 3 years of experience in building, integrating and supporting Web applications for mobile and desktop devices. Seeking to further IT career by growing with the team as IT professional.

Skills

- Front-end development
- JavaScript
- HTM
- CSS
- WordPress

- Bootstrap
- **JQuery**
- **TypeScript**
- Sounds knowledge of React, PHP and MS- Access

Experience

Associate Website Developer/ Affinity Express India Pvt Ltd

Oct 2022 - Dec 2023

Client: GoDaddy

- Design and develop responsive website for clients buissness
- Developed dynamic website that ensured fast page view rendering time and user experience using wordpess.
- Collaborated in creating and integrating visually captivating front-end designs into the WordPress platform.
- Handled website build on different builder such as Beaver Builder, WP Bakery, Visual Composer, Elementor.
- Website maintenance and security
- Photopea, Canva, PSD to HTML Conversion, V2-V3 conversion

Front-end Developer / Unplug Infinity Media Pvt Ltd

Nov 2019 - Oct 2022

Client: IYEDO

Design and develop responsive web application user interface for business clients.

- Developed dynamic interface that ensured fast page view rendering time and user experience using HTML 5.0, CSS3 JavaScript.
- JavaScript to handle complex form validation and dynamic form element updating.
- Developed page layouts and navigation and presented designs and concepts to clients and management review.
- Designed and developed User Interface using HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript Created sites using various Content Management Systems, and theming semantically with HTML, CSS and adding interactivity with JavaScript
- Developed application-level code to perform client-side validation using JavaScript.
- Designed UI architecture for internal web applications and worked with designers to construct conceptual wireframes and Mockups.

- In-Depth knowledge of web technologies and standards to deliver the best experiences across web and mobile devices including responsive Web UI.
- Maintained, enhanced, and recommended solutions that best suit business and technology need from UI standpoints.
- Implements cross-platform browser plugins, improving overall website responsiveness and functionality.

Project

1. Healthcare web application

Develop high-performance vendor-facing applications, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Built Custom components for UX-Library consisting of Filters, Dropdown, Carousel, Checkbox, Input, and Icons. Design reusable interface components with ES6 features.

2. Library Management System (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and PHP)

This is a management system developed for libraries. The traditional library's barriers and concerns are highlighted, and the libraries are promoted to have easy access. The librarian can add, amend, and delete student and book information in the Library Management system. Students get a unique ID that allows them to access any book in the library. The librarian can check the user's information, fine payment, and book information using the ID.

3. Coding Hunt (WordPress, Elementor)

This project is a blog on web development, featuring building blocks of web development essentials like HTML CSS and JAVASCRIPT. The reader will get vast knowledge of it and also communicate with the author for suggestions and feedback. Users can also participate in different coding challenges and win many rewards.

Education

2020 TO 2022

MCA (Data Science)/ Ajeenkya DY Patil University

MCA from ADYPU, Pune (Avg CGPA-8.85)

2014 TO 2020

BCA / Maharashtra Institute of Technology SOM,

Completed BCA from Maharashtra Institute of Technology SOM, Pune (52.37%)

2012 TO 2013

12th / Kendriya Vidyalaya Sangathan,

Completed 12th (PCMB) from Kendriya Vidyalaya AFS Ojhar, Nashik (61.0%)

2010 TO 2011

10th / Kendriya Vidyalaya Sangathan,

Completed 10th from Kendriya Vidyalaya Cantt, Kanpur (7.0 CGPA)

Certification

- TCS iON Career Edge Young Professional (10/2021)
- Statistics for Machine Learning (05/2021)

Date:

Place: Kanpur (UP)

Ashish Kumar